<modDesc descVersion="107">
    <author>Ritter</author>
    <version>1.1.4.0</version>
    <title>
        <en>Realistic Livestock - Ritter version</en>
        <it>Allevamento Realistico - Versione Ritter</it>
    </title>
    <description>
        <en>
            <![CDATA[Replaces FS25's simple animal clusters with individually tracked animals - each with unique genetics, breeding, diseases, and production traits. A maintained version of Arrow-kb's Realistic Livestock mod.

Every animal is tracked separately with its own identity, genetic makeup, health status, and production output. Genetics are inherited through breeding, diseases can spread and require treatment, and production is driven by each animal's individual traits.

This is a maintained version of the original Realistic Livestock mod by Arrow-kb, who has discontinued development. The goal is to keep the mod working, fix bugs, and make improvements where needed.

Notes:
- Based on Arrow-kb's Realistic Livestock mod (v1.2.0.5), released under GPL-3 license
- Savegame data from Arrow-kb's original version is automatically migrated on first load
- Font Library mod is no longer required
- Incompatible with FS25_EnhancedLivestock, FS25_MoreVisualAnimals, and FS25_EnhancedAnimalSystem

Documentation: https://rittermod.github.io/FS25_RealisticLivestockRM
Source code and issue tracker: https://github.com/rittermod/FS25_RealisticLivestockRM

Changelog

v1.1.4.0:
Hof Bergmann 1.4 support and bug fixes:
- Fixed horse breed visuals on Hof Bergmann: adult horses no longer display as foals, breed colors now match correctly, foal-to-adult model transition now works
- Fixed horse riding and equipment on Hof Bergmann v1.4: saddles, carriages, and tools from the Horse Addon Pack now attach correctly
- Disabled four horse breeds not natively supported by Hof Bergmann (Pinto, Chestnut, Bay, Dun) from the dealer - existing savegame horses of those breeds are unaffected
- Fixed dealer generating sale animals for breeds marked as not purchasable on the current map
- Fixed wool and chicken eggs not spawning on Hof Bergmann v1.4: bridge now remaps fillTypes to match HB's husbandry buildings
- Fixed Hof Bergmann egg incubator failing to add hatched chicks to husbandry when RLRM is active
- Fixed crash when animal output curve returns nil, which could silently stop all production in a building
- Added diagnostic logging for fillType mismatches in pallet and milk output

v1.1.3.0:
- Fixed bridge animals (rabbits, quail, etc.) getting duplicate IDs in multiplayer, causing animals to disappear on clients
- Fixed bridge animal ID counter, now tracks per-type counters with savegame persistence
- Fixed bulk buy silently failing when map husbandries reject animal breeds (e.g. Hereford in Hof Bergmann filtered pens)
- Existing saves with duplicate bridge animal IDs are automatically repaired on load
- Added pre-validation for bulk buy: shows which animals can't be purchased and why before confirming
- Added diagnostic logging for animal loading, breeding, and pack compatibility troubleshooting
- Added warnings when animals are lost due to removed packs or breed mismatches

]]>
        </en>
        <it>
            <![CDATA[Sostituisce i semplici cluster di animali di FS25 con animali individualmente tracciati, ciascuno con genetica unica, allevamento, malattie e tratti produttivi. Una versione mantenuta del mod Realistic Livestock di Arrow-kb.

Ogni animale viene monitorato separatamente con la propria identità, composizione genetica, stato di salute e produzione. La genetica si trasmette tramite riproduzione, le malattie possono diffondersi richiedendo trattamenti, e la produzione dipende dai tratti individuali di ciascun animale.

Questa è una versione mantenuta del mod originale Realistic Livestock di Arrow-kb, che ha interrotto lo sviluppo. L'obiettivo è mantenere il mod funzionante, correggere bug e apportare miglioramenti dove necessario.

Note:
- Basato sul mod Realistic Livestock di Arrow-kb (v1.2.0.5), rilasciato sotto licenza GPL-3
- I dati di salvataggio della versione originale di Arrow-kb vengono migrati automaticamente al primo caricamento
- Il mod Font Library non è più richiesto
- Incompatibile con FS25_EnhancedLivestock, FS25_MoreVisualAnimals e FS25_EnhancedAnimalSystem

Documentazione: https://rittermod.github.io/FS25_RealisticLivestockRM
Codice sorgente e tracciamento issue: https://github.com/rittermod/FS25_RealisticLivestockRM

]]>
        </it>
    </description>
    <iconFilename>icon_RealisticLivestock.dds</iconFilename>
    <multiplayer supported="true"/>
    <extraSourceFiles>
        <sourceFile filename="scripts/main.lua"/>
    </extraSourceFiles>
    <l10n filenamePrefix="translations/translation"/>
    <inputBinding>
        <actionBinding action="VisualAnimalsDialog">
            <binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="KEY_lshift KEY_t"/>
        </actionBinding>
        <actionBinding action="RL_OPEN_ANIMAL_SCREEN">
            <binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="KEY_r" index="1"/>
        </actionBinding>
        <actionBinding action="RL_MARK">
            <binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="KEY_x" index="1"/>
        </actionBinding>
        <actionBinding action="RL_MONITOR">
            <binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="KEY_m" index="1"/>
        </actionBinding>
        <actionBinding action="RL_AI">
            <binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="KEY_i" index="1"/>
        </actionBinding>
        <actionBinding action="RL_CASTRATE">
            <binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="KEY_c" index="1"/>
        </actionBinding>
        <actionBinding action="RL_DISEASES">
            <binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="KEY_d" index="1"/>
        </actionBinding>
        <actionBinding action="RL_SELECT">
            <binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="KEY_a" index="1"/>
        </actionBinding>
    </inputBinding>
    <actions>
        <action name="VisualAnimalsDialog"/>
        <action name="RL_OPEN_ANIMAL_SCREEN"/>
        <action name="RL_MARK"/>
        <action name="RL_MONITOR"/>
        <action name="RL_AI"/>
        <action name="RL_CASTRATE"/>
        <action name="RL_DISEASES"/>
        <action name="RL_SELECT"/>
    </actions>
    <helpLines>

        <category title="$l10n_rl_settings">

            <page title="$l10n_rl_help_monitors_title" iconSliceId="rlHelpIcons.monitor">

                <paragraph>
                    <text text="$l10n_rl_help_monitors_1"/>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph>
                    <text text="$l10n_rl_help_monitors_2"/>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph>
                    <text text="$l10n_rl_help_monitors_3"/>
                </paragraph>

            </page>

            <page title="$l10n_rl_help_pregnancy_title" iconSliceId="rlHelpIcons.pregnancy">

                <paragraph>
                    <text text="$l10n_rl_help_pregnancy_1"/>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph>
                    <text text="$l10n_rl_help_pregnancy_2"/>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph>
                    <text text="$l10n_rl_help_pregnancy_3"/>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph>
                    <text text="$l10n_rl_help_pregnancy_4"/>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph>
                    <text text="$l10n_rl_help_pregnancy_5"/>
                </paragraph>

            </page>

            <page title="$l10n_rl_help_production_title" iconSliceId="rlHelpIcons.production">

                <paragraph>
                    <text text="$l10n_rl_help_production_1"/>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph>
                    <text text="$l10n_rl_help_production_2"/>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph>
                    <text text="$l10n_rl_help_production_3"/>
                </paragraph>

            </page>

            <page title="$l10n_rl_help_weight_title" iconSliceId="gui.storeAttribute_maxLoadCapacity">

                <paragraph>
                    <text text="$l10n_rl_help_weight_1"/>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph>
                    <text text="$l10n_rl_help_weight_2"/>
                </paragraph>

            </page>

            <page title="$l10n_rl_help_genetics_title" iconSliceId="rlHelpIcons.genetics">

                <paragraph>
                    <text text="$l10n_rl_help_genetics_1"/>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph>
                    <text text="$l10n_rl_help_genetics_2"/>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph>
                    <text text="$l10n_rl_help_genetics_3"/>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph>
                    <text text="$l10n_rl_help_genetics_4"/>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph>
                    <text text="$l10n_rl_help_genetics_5"/>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph>
                    <text text="$l10n_rl_help_genetics_6"/>
                </paragraph>

            </page>

        </category>

    </helpLines>
</modDesc>